Kogoro Mouri disappears.
Kogoro Mouri menghilang.
But the fact was that he was working undercover in cooperation
Dia sebenarnya sedang melakukan penyelidikan penyamaran
with Inspector Megure to approach a band of robbers.
sekelompok pencuri dengan Inspektur Megure.
Mr. Head, the boss whose face is unknown,
Tapi Tn. Head, bos yang wajahnya tidak diketahui
sees through Kogoro's true identity
telah mengetahui penyamaran Kogoro
and requests him to do an unexpected investigation.
dan memintanya untuk melakukan penyelidikan.
She's a cute daughter, isn't she?
Seorang anak perempuan yang imut.
Ran!
Ran!
Why you... What're you up to?
Dasar berandal! Apa yang kau lakukan padanya?
It's up to you.
Itu tergantung padamu.
Darn it! What do you want?
Sial! Apa yang kau inginkan?
Just as expected of a great detective,
Kau sangat pengertian, Detektif.
Hurry spit it out!
Beritahu aku apa yang kau inginkan!
You deliberately disguised yourself
Kau mengalami kesulitan menyamar dirimu
and almost succeeded your mission.
dan menyusup ke dalam grupku.
So, just as scheduled,
Seperti yang direncanakan,
work along with my men as a skilled safe breaker.
kau akan bekerja dengan anak buahku sebagai ahli pembobol brankas.
What?
Apa?
The fact is...
Kebenarannya adalah...
Among my men, there's the one who killed my son.
salah satu anak buahku membunuh putraku.
I'd like you to determine who it is with your skills as a great detective
Aku ingin Detektif Kogoro Mouri yang hebat mengidentifikasi dia
by dawn, of the day after tomorrow.
sebelum dini hari dua hari dari sekarang.
What?
Apa?
Dawn day after tomorrow is also the time,
Pada waktu itu,
when we carry out our plan this time and leave Japan behind us.
setelah menyelesaikan pekerjaan ini, aku akan meninggalkan Jepang.
That's why I need you to do so by then.
Kau harus temukan dia sebelum itu.
What, after specifying who it is?
Apa yang terjadi setelah aku mengidentifikasi dia?
Are you planning to avenge the death of your son?
Apa kau akan membalaskan dendam putramu?
That's none of your business.
Itu bukan urusanmu.
But, if you refuse my request,
Tapi jika kau menolak...
you'll never see your daughter again.
Kau takkan pernah melihat putrimu lagi.
If the killer isn't instructed to cancel before the time limited by me,
Kecuali aku menelepon dia sebelum batas waktunya,
he will kill her.
seorang pembunuh yang kupekerjakan akan membunuh putrimu.
Don't tell me you had this in mind to begin with.
Apa kau sudah merencanakan ini?
Darn it!
Sial!
But I believe in...
Tapi aku percaya padamu.
Kogoro Mouri, your skills as a great detective!
Kogoro Mouri, aku tahu kau seorang detektif yang hebat.
What?
Apa?
Let's use the years we walked together as a springboard.
Didorong maju oleh tahun yang dihabiskan bersama.
And move forward full speed without slowing down.
Maju dengan kecepatan penuh tanpa memperlambat kecepatan.
Pops and I are in a Catch -22 situation.
Pria tua itu dan aku tersudut.
The unexpected purpose of the band of robbers.
Sekelompok pencuri itu punya tujuan yang mengejutkan.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan!
"The Great Detective is Manipulated (Part 2)"
"Detektif Hebat yang Dimanipulasi (Bagian 2)"
They haven't been found yet?
Masih belum menemukan mereka?
No, not yet! But time-wise,
Tidak, tuan. Tapi sulit untuk
it's hard to think that they got through the emergency alert.
membayangkan bagaimana mereka kabur dari penempatan darurat kita.
They probably have a secret hide-out somewhere.
Mereka pasti punya markas rahasia di suatu tempat.
And are waiting for a chance to flee.
Mereka mungkin sedang menunggu di sana untuk sebuah kesempatan untuk kabur.
The problem is where.
Jadi pertanyaannya adalah di mana markas mereka.
Darn it! All we got are the wallets of the customers!
Sial! Yang kita miliki adalah dompet mereka!
If we got the safe opened,
Kita akan mendapatkan lebih
it wouldn't have been anything like this!
jika kau membuka brankas itu!
Gosh. Why are you in a place like this?
Sial. Apa yang sedang kau lakukan di sini?
No, no, let me go!
Tidak! Lepaskan aku!
Cut out the fuss! I'll crush you!
Berhenti berteriak! Aku akan membunuhmu!
I'm scared!
Aku takut!
Cut out the noise, you brat!
Diam, nak!
Stop it! He's just a kid.
Berhenti! Dia hanya seorang anak kecil.
You're way noisier than he is!
Dan kau jauh lebih berisik dari dia.
-What? -What?
-Apa katamu? -Apa?
Cut it out, both of you!
Berhenti, kalian berdua!
Never mind that.
Bagaimanapun,
Mr. Head! I wanna ask you something!
Tn. Head, kami punya sebuah pertanyaan untukmu.
Why's Kogoro Mouri here?
Apa yang Kogoro Mouri lakukan di sini?
You brought him here!
Kau yang membawanya ke sini!
You better give me an answer that'll convince me!
Kau sebaiknya menjelaskan apa yang sedang terjadi!
Are you listening, Head?
Apa kau mendengarkan, Head?
Do you remember?
Apa kau ingat tempat ini?
This underground casino is the one that you guys attacked a year ago.
Itu kasino bawah tanah yang kau serang setahun yang lalu.
One of my comrades were killed there.
Salah satu anggotamu terbunuh di sana.
I want to know the truth of what happened a year ago.
Aku ingin detektif hebat Kogoro Mouri
In other words, I asked the Great Detective Kogoro Mouri
menentukan siapa yang membunuh putraku setahun yang lalu.
He was your son?
Dia adalah putramu?
That good-for-nothing brat?
Berandal tak berguna itu?
It's a first.
Itu berita untukku.
Oh, what a surprise.
Aku terkejut.
It's best to leave things like these up to specialists, you see.
Aku pikir aku mempekerjakan seorang yang profesional.
I'm counting on you, Great Detective.
Aku mengandalkanmu, Detektif.
Leave it to me. But, don't forget.
Serahkan padaku. Tapi kita punya sebuah perjanjian, bukan?
Good luck.
Itu tidak sesuai dengan masalahnya.
Pim...
Pim...
Mr. Pimple was killed by the people at the underground casino.
Tn. Pimple dibunuh oleh orang-orang kasino bawah tanah.
You were convinced of that a year ago, too.
Aku pikir kau sudah menerima itu setahun yang lalu.
Why bring it up again like this?
Kenapa kau mengungkitnya sekarang?
Not worth it!
Ini bodoh!
I can't be playing along with this!
Aku tidak punya waktu untuk permainan ini.
What?
Apa?
It won't open!
Itu tak mau terbuka!
Just what are you up to?
Kau pikir apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
When the time comes,
Ketika waktunya tiba,
the lock of the door will open automatically.
pintunya akan terbuka secara otomatis.
If you try to flee before that...
Jika kau berusaha untuk kabur sebelum itu...
There's no guarantee that you'll live.
Kau akan mati.
Hey, hold it! I've got nothing to do with this.
Tunggu! Ini tidak ada kaitannya denganku!
I was just waiting in the car like usual, you know!
Aku sedang menunggu di luar dengan mobil!
I heard that Pim was killed after everything happened, too!
Aku tidak dengar tentang kematian Pim hingga beberapa waktu kemudian!
Then, let's go over the details of the incident
Mari kita ulas keadaan setahun yang lalu.
It may have been my mistake
Memasukkan Tn. Pimple ke dalam pekerjaan itu
to add Mr. Pimple to the job we did a year ago.
mungkin adalah kesalahanku.
I'm sorry!
Maafkan aku!
Come on. Be more careful, will you?
Hati-hati.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
He stood out so much.
Dia menarik perhatian.
Talk about a good-for-nothing brat...
Dia tidak berguna.
Making him go there beforehand was just a waste of time.
Aku tidak tahu kenapa kami mengutusnya masuk lebih dulu.
Wanna crush him once?
Haruskah aku menghajarnya?
It's about time we go.
Ayo kita bergerak.
What?
Apa?
Nobody move! Hands in the air!
Jangan bergerak! Angkat tangan!
Do as you're told!
Lakukan seperti yang disuruh!
If you resist, I'll crush you!
Melawan dan aku akan membunuhmu!
Put the wallets in there!
Letakkan dompet kalian di sana!
Hey! Hurry it up!
Hei, cepat!
-What's going on? -What's up?
-Apa yang sedang terjadi? -Ada apa?
Help!
Tolong!
-What is it? Gunshots! -I'm scared!
-Apa yang terjadi? Tembakan? -Aku takut!
-The lights are back on! -Is he dead?
-Mereka kembali menyala? -Apa dia tewas?
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
Fire!
Tembak!
-Run! -Hurry! I don't want to die!
-Lari! -Cepat! Aku tidak mau mati!
Run for it!
Lari!
So Mr. Pimple was found,
Jasad tak dikenal
as a burnt unidentified body from the burnt remains.
Tn. Pimple ditemukan dalam puing-puing yang terbakar.
But this is based only on what you guys reported to me.
Itu yang kau laporkan padaku.
Just what do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
Look at this.
Lihat ini.
This is the image that was found on the security camera
Ini adalah rekaman dari kamera kasino bawah tanah.
Great Detective.
Detektif.
Does looking at this bring any questions to mind?
Apa ada yang tampak aneh bagimu?
What? Yeah.
Hah? Ya...
Well...
Aku tidak yakin.
Back then, you were disguised as customers and snuck in, right?
Kau menyamar dirimu sebagai tamu dan menyelinap masuk, bukan?
Yeah. That's why we let Pim in first
Ya. Itu sebabnya kami mengutus Pim masuk dulu
and made him hide the guns and knives.
untuk menyembunyikan senjata dan pisaunya.
Mr. Pim was disguised as a waiter, right?
Pim menyamar sebagai pelayan, bukan?
That's right, although it turned out that way.
Ya, walau kau lihat bagaimana hasilnya.
He was crushed because he asked for it.
Dia terbunuh.
That's right.
Itu benar.
And? Is there anything else?
Kau dapat yang lain?
The floor is spic-and-span.
Lantainya mengkilap.
It's called marble, right? That floor.
Itu terbuat dari marmer, bukan?
True.
Kau benar.
So, what about it?
Tapi lalu kenapa?
Darn it. Shape up, man.
Sial. Kendalikan dirimu.
Hey.
Hei.
That wound on your finger, did somebody bite you?
Apa kau mendapat luka di jarimu dari seseorang yang menggigitmu?
What?
Hah?
This is...
Aku mendapatkan ini ketika...
I was bitten by a dog, long time ago.
ada seekor anjing yang menggigitku dulu.
The knife, too?
Dan pisaumu?
Because there's a scratch
Ada bekas gigitan di pegangan pisaumu juga.
Yeah.
Yah.
I jokingly scared it. It bit my hand and knife.
Aku mengancamnya untuk main-main, dan dia menggigit tangan dan pisauku.
Strange. No dog was seen on the screen at the casino.
Itu aneh. Tidak ada anjing di dalam kasino itu.
What?
Apa?
But, in the image where Mr. Pin was lying on the floor a while ago...
Tapi video Pim yang berada di lantai...
Help!
Tolong!
-What is it? Gunshots! -I'm scared!
-Apa yang terjadi? Tembakan? -Aku takut!
The lights are back on!
Mereka kembali menyala?
-Is he dead? -What happened?
-Apa dia tewas? -Apa yang terjadi?
Pim?
Pim?
I see! The dog that you're referring to is Mr. Pim, right?
Itu dia! Anjing yang kau sebut sebenarnya adalah Tn. Pim!
Look! There's blood on his mouth!
Lihat! Ada darah di mulutnya!
It's just a coincidence!
Itu suatu kebetulan!
I was bitten by a dog in the neighborhood.
Aku digigit seekor anjing di lingkunganku.
Then, show me your knife!
Maka tunjukkan pada kami pisaumu!
Just by looking at it,
Aku akan tahu
we can tell if it's the teeth of a human's or a dog's!
apa itu bekas gigitan anjing atau manusia!
Crap!
Jangan konyol!
He was shot to death!
Seseorang menembak mati dia!
My knife had nothing to do with it!
Pisauku tidak ada hubungannya dengan itu!
Awesome!
Keren!
This is called an automatic, right?
Ini otomatis, bukan?
When you fire, the cartridges fall to the floor
Itu melontarkan selongsong
and bounce making clanking sounds.
ketika kau menembakkan suara gemerincing di lantai.
I see. The sound!
Itu dia. Suara itu!
Let me see the place that Mr. Pim was shot one more time!
Putar video saat Tn. Pin ditembak lagi.
Right after the gunshot that was heard during the blackout,
Tepat setelah tembakan selama pemadaman itu,
I'm sure you didn't hear the cartridge bounce on the floor!
aku tidak mendengar adanya selongsong yang jatuh ke lantai.
Help!
Tolong!
-What is it? A gunshot! -I'm scared!
-Apa yang terjadi? Tembakan? -Aku takut!
The lights are back on!
Mereka kembali menyala?
Which means... it was a revolver?
Yang artinya... itu sebuah revolver?
Exactly!
Itu benar!
Hey, hey. As you can see, this is an automatic.
Tunggu. Ini adalah otomatis.
Maybe another one was snuck in or something.
Mungkin kau punya senjata kedua.
If so, it would be impossible to get through the metal detector.
Tapi itu akan mustahil untuk melalui pendeteksi metal.
It's neither ceramic nor plastic...
Jika itu dibuat oleh... bukan keramik atau plastik,
If it's made of...
tapi hal lain...
I see. Resin!
Itu dia! Resin!
If the gun is made of resin,
Jika senjatanya dibuat oleh resin,
the metal detector won't detect it!
pendeteksi metal takkan menemukannya.
Furthermore, if such a thing were to be prepared beforehand,
Dan jika pelaku telah menyiapkan sebuah senjata resin,
it was contemplated murder!
maka itu artinya pembunuhan itu sudah direncanakan.
There's no way that it would be someone from the casino side.
Tidak mungkin seseorang seperti itu akan bekerja untuk kasino
Because they would've known nothing about the attack on the casino!
karena mereka tidak tahu kasino akan diserang.
It's only an assumption but during the blackout,
Pertama, Tn. Mouth menggunakan pisau
first Mr. Mouth uses his knife to render Mr. Pimple motionless.
untuk membuat Tn. Pimple tetap diam selama pemadaman,
Then, Mr. Eyes fires the bullet.
lalu Tn. Eyes menembaknya,
And made it look as if
membuatnya terlihat seperti
somebody from the underground casino did it.
para pegawai kasino yang membunuhnya.
Then, are you saying that Mr. Mouth and I are the ones who did it?
Lalu, maksudmu Tn. Mouth dan aku yang melakukannya?
Right!
Itu benar!
Why don't we try it out, then, Mr. Great Detective?
Maka mari kita coba, Tn. Detektif.
What?
Apa?
Isn't that why you went all out
Bukankah itu sebabnya
and made a grand set like this, right, Mr. Head?
kau mendirikan set ini, Tn. Head?
What's the matter? Exhausted or what?
Ada apa? Apa kau lelah?
Or have you run out of battery?
Atau apa kau kehabisan baterai?
That's a good one.
Kau pantas mendapatkannya.
Never mind.
Terserah.
A year ago...
Setahun yang lalu...
If Pimple was standing there before the blackout,
Jika Pimple sedang berdiri di sana sebelum pemadaman,
I was standing around here.
maka aku sedang berdiri di sekitar sini.
It seems that the place I'm in is here.
Sepertinya aku di sini.
I'm here.
Aku di sini.
The blackout was 10 seconds.
Pemadaman itu berlangsung 10 detik.
The gunshot was heard 5 seconds after the blackout.
Tembakan itu terjadi 5 detik setelah lampunya mati.
That's about it, I think. Right, Mr. Great Detective?
Bukankah itu benar, Detektif?
Yeah.
Ya.
Then, here goes.
Ayo kita mulai.
Okay!
Baik.
Start!
Mulai!
Help!
Tolong!
-What is it? A gunshot! -I'm scared!
-Apa yang terjadi? Tembakan? -Aku takut!
It's dark!
Gelap!
The lights are back on!
Mereka kembali menyala?
Time out.
Waktu habis.
I guess it really wasn't like this.
Tapi bukan ini yang terjadi.
We barely made it.
Kita hampir tidak sempat.
In the dark of the blackout, it was panic.
Selama pemadaman, semua orang akan panik.
No good.
Aku salah.
So, it's almost dawn.
Sudah hampir dini hari.
What now, Great Detective?
Apa yang akan kau lakukan, Detektif?
What a goofy detective.
Dia payah.
He should be crushed after all.
Kita harus membunuhnya.
Hey, why did everybody close their eyes before the blackout?
Hei, kenapa kau memejamkan matamu sebelum pemadaman?
But only Mr. Pim like the other customers didn't close his eyes.
Tapi seperti tamu lainnya, Pim tidak memejamkan matanya.
I got it!
Itu dia!
You guys knew that the blackout would occur beforehand.
Kau tahu lampunya akan mati.
Then, you set a timer onto the supply transfer panel
Tidak, kau mengatur waktu pada saklarnya,
so that the blackout would occur at a set time.
jadi lampunya akan padam pada waktu tertentu.
Nobody move! Hands in the air!
Jangan bergerak! Angkat tangan!
Do as you're told!
Lakukan seperti yang disuruh!
If you resist, I'll crush you!
Melawan dan aku akan membunuhmu!
Put the wallets in there!
Letakkan dompet kalian di sana!
Hey! Hurry it up!
Hei, cepat!
Don't move!
Jangan bergerak!
-What is it? Gunshot! -I'm scared!
-Apa yang terjadi? Tembakan? -Aku takut!
The lights are back on!
Mereka kembali menyala?
-Is he dead? -What happened?
-Apa dia tewas? -Apa yang terjadi?
-Fire! -Help!
-Tembak! -Tolong!
It's obvious that you guys are the ones who set this fire, too.
Kau juga yang memulai penembakan
In order to escape and get rid of the evidence.
agar kau bisa kabur dan menghancurkan buktinya.
You idiot!
Kau bodoh!
That's why I told you to throw that away immediately.
Aku sudah menyuruhmu untuk membuangnya!
Shut up! This is my partner!
Diam! Ini adalah rekanku!
Shut up!
Diam!
I've done my job, Mr. Head!
Aku melakukan tugasku, Tn. Head!
Tell the killer to stop the killing right away!
Sekarang hentikan pembunuhnya!
Don't lay a finger on my daughter Ran!
Jangan sakiti putriku!
I knew it.
Aku tahu itu.
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
Nothing. It's nothing.
Bukan apa-apa.
Rather, is the detective's deduction for real?
Bagaimanapun, apakah detektif itu benar?
Yeah, you did splendid, Great Detective.
Ya. Aku terkesan, Detektif.
Out of all people, Pim found out about our plan to kill Mr. Head
Pim mengetahui rencana kami untuk membunuh Tn. Head
and take the loot for ourselves.
dan mengambil uang itu untuk diri kami sendiri.
Well, we had no other choice, you see.
Kami harus membunuhnya.
The same this time, too!
Seperti yang kami lakukan sekarang!
We've finally met, Mr. Head!
Kita akhirnya bertemu, Tn. Head!
What?
Apa?
Conan?
Conan?
Ran. If you're safe,
Ran. Jika kau tidak apa-apa,
please contact Inspector Megure right away.
segera hubungi Inspektur Megure dan minta perlindungan.
Pops and I are fine.
Pria tua itu dan aku baik-baik saja.
We're with the band of robbers.
Kami sedang bersama dengan kelompok pencuri itu.
The place is at the warehouse district by the harbor.
Kami berada di sebuah gudang di pelabuhan.
For details, check the GPS.
Aku akan kirimkan rinciannya pada GPS-mu.
What? What does he mean by if I'm safe?
Apa maksudmu, jika aku baik-baik saja?
But at any rate, I'd better call Inspector Megure!
Bagaimanapun, aku harus menelepon Inspektur Megure.
The detection system of the auto control...
Sebuah sistem sensor otomatis.
Remote controlling it from inside your pocket.
Kau mengendalikannya dengan sebuah remote di sakumu.
And this is...
Apa ini?
It's the image of the security camera
Rekaman ini dari kamera kasino bawah tanah itu.
I asked the Great Detective Kogoro Mouri
Aku ingin detektif hebat Kogoro Mouri
to figure out who killed my son.
untuk menentukan siapa yang membunuh putraku setahun yang lalu.
You recorded your own voice that you processed
Kau merekam suaramu
and played it with the remote controller,
dan menggunakan remote ini untuk memutarnya kembali
and acted out a client with no face.
untuk menggambarkan sosok klien tanpa wajah.
You did it wanting to avenge the death of your son?
Apa kau berusaha untuk membalaskan dendam putramu?
What clowns we were.
Kau membodohi kami.
I gave birth to him when I was 15.
Aku melahirkan dia ketika usiaku 15 tahun.
Sending him out to a foster home
Sebuah kesalahan menyerahkan dia untuk adopsi
wanting him to lead a normal life was my mistake.
agar dia bisa memiliki kehidupan yang lebih baik.
On top of becoming a delinquent,
Pada akhirnya,
he was hired even without knowing who I was.
dia dipekerjakan tanpa menyadari siapa aku.
How ironic.
Itu ironis.
Sorry, Mr. Detective.
Maaf, Detektif.
I'm sorry for getting you messed up in this too, sonny.
Maaf kau juga terlibat.
I'll instruct the killer to stop the deal right away.
Aku akan beritahu sang pembunuh untuk mundur.
Are you sure?
Benarkah?
What're you doing?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
Are you planning to die with them?
Apa kau akan mati dengan mereka
To compensate the death of your son?
untuk menebus kematian putramu?
If so, take a look!
Maka lihatlah ini.
Mr. Pimple is still alive!
Tn. Pimple masih hidup.
Look carefully at his mouth.
Lihat mulutnya baik-baik.
He saying something.
Dia mengatakan sesuatu.
Mother, don't already. Cut it out.
Tolong berhenti... Ibu...
It seems he knew that you, Ms. Lip was in fact Mr. Head
Dia tahu kau, Nona Lip adalah Tn. Head
and his mother as well.
dan ibunya.
Or it could be that he decided to deliberately get hired by you
Mungkin dia mengambil pekerjaan itu
to stop you from committing crimes.
agar kau akan mengakhiri kehidupan burukmu.
No way.
Tidak...
If he's alive,
Jika dia masih hidup,
I'm sure he would stop you again like he did there.
dia mungkin akan berusaha untuk menghentikanmu lagi.
-Mr. Mouri! -Conan!
-Mouri! -Conan!
Hey! Don't die!
Hei! Jangan mati!
You gotta contact the killer! Please...
Telepon pembunuhnya! Tolong...
Darn it!
Sial!
Ran...
Ran...
Ms. Ran Mouri?
Kau pasti Ran Mouri.
I've come for you.
Aku datang untuk menjemputmu.
Yes.
Baik.
-Please get in. -Okay.
-Masuk ke dalam mobil. -Baik.
Don't get in! Ran!
Jangan masuk, Ran!
Darn it!
Sial!
Run for it!
Lari!
Come here, you!
Kemarilah, kau!
Dad?
Ayah?
Ran!
Ran!
Are you all right?
Apa kau baik-baik saja?
Dad, you're hurting me.
Ayah, kau menyakitiku.
I was... I was so worried.
Aku... aku sangat cemas!
I made it.
Kita berhasil.
Ms. Lip was shot by Mr. Eyes
Setelah ditembak oleh Tn. Eyes,
and was taken to an emergency hospital
Nona Lip dibawa ke rumah sakit.
and somehow made it through.
Dia selamat
The band of robbers was all arrested.
dan kelompok pencuri itu ditahan.
I really worried about both of you, you know.
Aku sangat mencemaskan kalian berdua.
Are you guys listening?
Apa kau mendengarkan?
Dad? Conan?
Ayah? Conan?
I'm listening so give me another shot, will you?
Aku mendengarkan, jadi tuangkan lagi untukku.
I'm listening, so let me sleep.
Aku mendengarkan, jadi biarkan aku tidur.
What's with you two?
Ada apa dengan kalian berdua?
"Next Episode" -We formed a group
"Episode Selanjutnya" -Grup kami dibentuk
to protect the peace and safety of the people.
untuk melindungi kedamaian dan keamanan masyarakat.
The silver detective squad!
Para Detektif Perak!
What is it?
Ada apa?
Which means, I'm you? Conan?
Apa itu menjadikan aku dirimu, Conan?
You don't have to go out of your way to overlay yourselves with us.
Kau tidak perlu memaksakan perbandingannya.
It looks like things are going to get complicated again.
Aku mencium masalah.
Next Conan, "The Boy Detectives VS. the Silver Detectives"
Selanjutnya dalam Conan, "Para Detektif Cilik vs Para Detektif Perak"
Next Conan's Hint:
Petunjuk Conan Selanjutnya:
"Aloha shirt"
"Sebuah kemeja Hawaii"
-Go to the bank on Golden Week. -Why?
-Mari kita pergi ke bank selama Minggu Emas. -Kenapa?
Maybe you can come up with lots of "golden" benefits.
Karena keuntungan kita akan "berbunga"!
Just kidding.
Hanya bercanda.